var ObjQuestion=[{"Quest_Id":"1","Chapter_Id":"1","Question":"Minimum equipment of signal in &quot;B&quot; Class single line TAST are &ndash;<br/>?? ????? ????? ???? TAST ??? ?? ?? ?? ????? ?????&ndash;"},{"Quest_Id":"2","Chapter_Id":"1","Question":"Speed of a train whose driving cab is defective<br/>??? ????????? ??? ???? ?? ?? ???? ?? ??? ????&ndash;"},{"Quest_Id":"3","Chapter_Id":"1","Question":"Percentage of brake power for C.C.rakes from originating station<br/>?????????? ?????? ?? ???? ??? ?? ????? ???? ?? ??????? ????&ndash;"},{"Quest_Id":"4","Chapter_Id":"1","Question":"Reminder caution order has been numbered as/<br/>????????? ????? ????? ?? ?????? ??&ndash;"},{"Quest_Id":"5","Chapter_Id":"1","Question":"If a train is caught in cyclone/storm Loco Pilot should&ndash;<br/>??? ??? ???? ???????? ????&ndash;????? ??? ??? ???? ?? ???? ????? ??&ndash;"},{"Quest_Id":"6","Chapter_Id":"1","Question":"Advance authority to pass a defective reception signal of a station at ON is<br/>???? ???? ????? ?? ??? ???? ?? ?????? ????????? ??&ndash;"},{"Quest_Id":"7","Chapter_Id":"1","Question":"Shunting speed of vehicle with highly inflammable is<br/>??? ??????????? ???? ?? ?????? ????? ??&ndash;"},{"Quest_Id":"8","Chapter_Id":"1","Question":"In case relief train failed in auto block section, LP should protect in rear<br/>??? ??? ????? ???? ???? ?????? ?????? ??? ??? ?? ???? ?? ???? ????? ?? ???? ??? ?????????? ???? ?????&ndash;"},{"Quest_Id":"9","Chapter_Id":"1","Question":"Effective substitute for signal over lap is/<br/>????? ?????? ?? ???????? ?????????? ????? ??? ?? ??? ?? ??&ndash;"},{"Quest_Id":"10","Chapter_Id":"1","Question":"Last stop signal of a &quot;C&quot; class station in MOMA D/line section is:<br/>???? ????? ???? ?????????? ???? ?????? ??? ??? ??? ?? ???? ?? ?????? ?? ?? ????? ??? ????? ????&ndash;"},{"Quest_Id":"11","Chapter_Id":"1","Question":"Block overlap is provided for<br/> ????? ?????? ???? ???? ???&ndash;"},{"Quest_Id":"12","Chapter_Id":"1","Question":"In the leading cab normaly the person can travel including crew&ndash;<br/>?????? ??? ??? ????????? ?????? ?? ???? ???? ??????? ?? ?????? ???? ??????? ?? ???&ndash;"},{"Quest_Id":"13","Chapter_Id":"1","Question":"In speedometer becomes defective enroute Loco pilot shall work the train at a speed &ndash;<br/> ??? ?????? ??? ??? ???? ????? ???? ?? ??? ?? ???? ??&ndash;"},{"Quest_Id":"14","Chapter_Id":"1","Question":"For shunting purposes coupling and un&ndash;coupling of engine can be done <br/>&ndash;?????? ?? ????? ??? ???? ?? ????? ?? ????? ??.? ?? ?? ?????&ndash;"},{"Quest_Id":"15","Chapter_Id":"2","Question":"Catenary is the part of -कैटनरी एक भाग है -"},{"Quest_Id":"16","Chapter_Id":"2","Question":"TFWA is a /             टीएफडब्ल्यूए है एक-"},{"Quest_Id":"17","Chapter_Id":"2","Question":"If receiver are connected in parallel the voltage on each receiver is -यदि रिसिवर को समानन्तर में जोड़ा जाए तो प्रत्येक रिसिवर का वोल्टेज होगा-"},{"Quest_Id":"18","Chapter_Id":"2","Question":"The contactor for MVMT2 is  /          MVMT2 का कान्टेक्टर है-"},{"Quest_Id":"19","Chapter_Id":"2","Question":"If both panto not raising fuse to be checked                अगर दोनों पेन्टो न उठे तो फ्यूज चेक करेगे-"},{"Quest_Id":"20","Chapter_Id":"2","Question":"The normal height of contact wire from the rail head is रेल हेड से कान्टेक्ट तार की सामान्य ऊचाई होती है -"},{"Quest_Id":"21","Chapter_Id":"2","Question":"TFWR is a  /  TFWRहै एक -"},{"Quest_Id":"22","Chapter_Id":"2","Question":"Parking brake applied automatically By putting-पार्किंग ब्रेक स्वतः लगेगी-"},{"Quest_Id":"23","Chapter_Id":"2","Question":"For glowing marker red we should operate switchअगर मार्कर की लाल बत्ती जलानी हो तब निम्न में से कौन से स्वीच के द्वारा संभव है-"},{"Quest_Id":"24","Chapter_Id":"2","Question":"Voltage remains same in a circuit connected as -वोल्टेज समान रहता है जब परिपथ जुड़ा हो   -"},{"Quest_Id":"25","Chapter_Id":"2","Question":"Voltmeter is always connected with source of supply inवोल्टमीटर को सदा किस सोर्स आॅॅफ सप्लाई से जोड.े जाते हैं"},{"Quest_Id":"26","Chapter_Id":"2","Question":"Maximum staggering of OHE in straight may beवोएचई का अधिकतम स्टैगरिंग स्टेट लाईन में हो सकता है-"},{"Quest_Id":"27","Chapter_Id":"2","Question":"Switch provided to start the blowers to cool the Traction motor in WAG-9 locoडब्ल्युएजी-9 लोको में ट्रैक्शन मोटर को ठंडा करने के लिये लगे ब्लोअर को चलाने का स्वीच है-"},{"Quest_Id":"28","Chapter_Id":"2","Question":"If HMCS-2 is put on III then it isolate/     जब एचएमसीएस-2 को प्प्प् में रखा जाता है तब आइसोलेट होता है-"},{"Quest_Id":"29","Chapter_Id":"2","Question":"In WAG-9 loco MRs are located in-डब्ल्युएजी-9 लोको में एमआर लगे है -"},{"Quest_Id":"30","Chapter_Id":"2","Question":"Rating of CCPT in locomotiveसीसीपीटी का रेटिंग है -"}];
var Options=[{"Quest_Id":"1","Opt1":"Outer,Home,Starter<br/>????, ???,????????","Opt2":"Warner,Home,Starter<br/>?????, ???,????????","Opt3":"Outer & Home<br/>???? ??? ???","Ans":"Opt1"},{"Quest_Id":"2","Opt1":"40 KMPH 40<br/>???????????","Opt2":"25 KMPH 25<br/>???????????","Opt3":"Normal speed<br/>??????? ???","Ans":"Opt3"},{"Quest_Id":"3","Opt1":"0.85","Opt2":"1","Opt3":"0.95","Ans":"Opt2"},{"Quest_Id":"4","Opt1":"T/409","Opt2":"T/A 409","Opt3":"T/B 409","Ans":"Opt2"},{"Quest_Id":"5","Opt1":"Not stop his train<br/>???? ??? ???? ???? ??","Opt2":"Stop his train immediately<br/>???? ????? ??? ???? ??","Opt3":"Stop his train after clearing curve, tunnel, bridge etc.<br/>???, ?????, ??? ??? ?? ???? ??? ???? ??? ???? ??","Ans":"Opt1"},{"Quest_Id":"6","Opt1":"T/369(3b)","Opt2":"T/369(i)","Opt3":"T/511","Ans":"Opt2"},{"Quest_Id":"7","Opt1":"5 KMPH","Opt2":"8 KMPH","Opt3":"15 KMPH","Ans":"Opt2"},{"Quest_Id":"8","Opt1":"600&ndash;600&ndash;10&ndash;10&ndash;45M red hand signal","Opt2":"250&ndash;250&ndash;10&ndash;45M red hand signal","Opt3":"90&ndash;90&ndash;10&ndash;45M red hand signal","Ans":"Opt3"},{"Quest_Id":"9","Opt1":"Catch siding<br/>??? ???????","Opt2":"Dead end<br/>??? ????","Opt3":"Sand hump<br/>???? ????","Ans":"Opt1"},{"Quest_Id":"10","Opt1":"Advance starter<br/>?????? ????????","Opt2":"Starter<br/>????????","Opt3":"Home Signal<br/>??? ?????","Ans":"Opt1"},{"Quest_Id":"11","Opt1":"Taking off home signal<br/>??? ????? ???? ?? ???","Opt2":"Granting line clear for a train<br/>????? ?? ???? ?????? ???? ?? ???","Opt3":"Taking off the Last stop signal<br/>?????? ??? ????? ???? ?? ???","Ans":"Opt2"},{"Quest_Id":"12","Opt1":"5","Opt2":"4","Opt3":"3","Ans":"Opt2"},{"Quest_Id":"13","Opt1":"10% less than the maximum permissible speed<br/>?????? ????? ??? ?? 10? ??? ???.? ??? ???? ??","Opt2":"10% less than the booked speed<br/>????? ??? ?? 10% ?? ??? ???? ??? ???? ????? ????","Opt3":"10% less the permissible speed<br/>????? ??? ?? 10? ?? ??? ???.? ??? ???? ?????","Ans":"Opt1"},{"Quest_Id":"14","Opt1":"By engine crew only<br/>???? ?? ??","Opt2":"By traffic staff only<br/>???? ??????? ?????? ?? ??","Opt3":"Both by engine crew and traffic staff<br/>???? ?? ??????? ????? ?????  ?? ???? ?? ?? ??????","Ans":"Opt3"},{"Quest_Id":"15","Opt1":"OHE<br/>","Opt2":"Pantograph<br/>/ पेन्टोग्राफ","Opt3":"Motor<br/>/ मोटर","Ans":"Opt1"},{"Quest_Id":"16","Opt1":"Step Down Transformer<br/>स्टेप डाउन ट्रान्सफर्मर ","Opt2":"Step Up Transformer<br/>स्टेप अप ट्रान्सफर्मर","Opt3":"Auto Transformer<br/>आॅटो ट्रान्सफर्मर","Ans":"Opt3"},{"Quest_Id":"17","Opt1":"Same<br/>समान","Opt2":"More<br/>अधिक","Opt3":"Less<br/>कम","Ans":"Opt2"},{"Quest_Id":"18","Opt1":"C-106<br/>","Opt2":"C-107<br/>","Opt3":"C-111<br/>","Ans":"Opt2"},{"Quest_Id":"19","Opt1":"CCPT only<br/>सिर्फ सीसीपीटी","Opt2":"CCBA and CCPT<br/>सीसीबीए और सीसीपीटी","Opt3":"CCBA only<br/>सिर्फ सीसीबीए","Ans":"Opt1"},{"Quest_Id":"20","Opt1":"4.65 M<br/>","Opt2":"5.55 M<br/>","Opt3":"5.65 M<br/>","Ans":"Opt2"},{"Quest_Id":"21","Opt1":"Auto transformer<br/>अत्यधिक करेंट","Opt2":"Stepup transformer<br/>स्टेपअप ट्रन्सफर्मर","Opt3":"Step Dn transformer<br/>स्टेपडाउन ट्रन्सफर्मर","Ans":"Opt2"},{"Quest_Id":"22","Opt1":"BL key from “D” <br/>आॅटो ट्रन्सफर्मर ","Opt2":"Reversor on “O”<br/>रिवर्सर को “0” पर लाने पर","Opt3":"ZPT on “Dn”<br/>जेडपीटी को डाउन में लाने पर","Ans":"Opt3"},{"Quest_Id":"23","Opt1":"BLPRR<br/>बीएल चाभी को “डी” से आॅफ में लाने पर","Opt2":"BLPRD<br/>बीएलपीआरडी","Opt3":"BLZLF<br/>बीएलजेडएलएफ ","Ans":"Opt1"},{"Quest_Id":"24","Opt1":"Parallel<br/>समान्तर	","Opt2":"Series<br/>श्रेणीबद्ध","Opt3":"Both<br/>दोना","Ans":"Opt1"},{"Quest_Id":"25","Opt1":"Parallel<br/>पैरेलल","Opt2":"Series<br/>सिरिज","Opt3":"None of the above<br/>कोई नहीं","Ans":"Opt2"},{"Quest_Id":"26","Opt1":"20 cms<br/>20 सीएम","Opt2":"27 to 30 cms<br/>27 से 30 सीएम","Opt3":"24 cms<br/>24 सीएम","Ans":"Opt2"},{"Quest_Id":"27","Opt1":"ZBAN<br/>","Opt2":"BLVMT<br/>","Opt3":"None<br/>कुछ नहीं","Ans":"Opt1"},{"Quest_Id":"28","Opt1":"TM-3<br/>","Opt2":"TM-5<br/>","Opt3":"TM-4<br/>","Ans":"Opt3"},{"Quest_Id":"29","Opt1":"Machine Room<br/>मशीन रूम में","Opt2":"Side of Under frame<br/>अन्डर फ्रेम के बगल में","Opt3":"Under frame<br/>अन्डर फ्रेम में","Ans":"Opt1"},{"Quest_Id":"30","Opt1":"16A<br/>","Opt2":"35A<br/>","Opt3":"6A<br/>","Ans":"Opt2"}];
